Register to the Papers of Vladimir and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz
Yale University Music Library
- ITEMS FROM THE LIBRARY OF VLADIMIR HOROWITZ, 1784-1986; Series VII; 21 boxes (8.75')
  - Manuscript and Printed Music From the Library of Vladimir Horowitz, VII.A
    - Sonata for piano, opus 26. June 1949., Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981
      37 p.
      Photocopy of manuscript; corrected copy, dated 8/30/49 (in pencil).
    - Souveniers., Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981
      Photocopy of manuscript. Contents: I Tempo di Walzer. II Schottisch. III Adagio. IV Galop.
    - XVII and XVIII Century Italian Cembalo and Organ Music / Transcribed for the Piano [by] Béla Bartók. New York: Carl Fischer Inc., 1930., Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945
      Includes: Marcello, Benedetto. Sonata. (11 p.).-- Rossi, Michelangelo. Toccata (No. 1). (9 p.).-- Rossi, Michelangelo. Toccata (No. 2). (9 p.).-- Rossi, Michelangelo. Tre Correnti. (7 p.). -- Ciaia, Azzolino Bernardo della. Sonata. I. Toccata. (9 p.). -- II. Canzone. (11 p.). -- III. Primo Tempo. (5 p.). -- IV. Secondo Tempo. (5 p.). -- Frescobaldi, Girolamo. Toccata. (9 p.). -- Frescobaldi, Girolamo. Fuga. (7 p.). -- Zipoli, Domenico. Pastorale. (7 p.).
      Pl. nos.: 25268-14, 25269-7, 25270-7, 25271-5, 25272-7, 25273-10, 25274-4, 25275-4, 25276-7, 25277-6, 25278-5.
    - Concerto no. V in E-flat major for the piano, opus 73. New York: G. Schirmer, 1929., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 85, Folder 11)
      70 p.
      Plate number: 15415
      Edited and notated by Franz Kullak.
    - Grande sonate pathétique pour le pianoforte, op. 13. Berlin: Bote & G. Bock, n.d. [c.1838], Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
      17 p.
      Plate number: B. et B. 96
    - Klaviersonate in C-dur op. 55 (Waldsteinsonate)., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 85, Folder 12)
      64 p.
      Facsimile. Number 273. Card laid inside front cover from Rudolf and Irene Serkin, 1959 Oct. 1.
    - Klaviersonate in C-moll, op. 111. [facsimile] München: Drei Masken Verlages, 1922., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 85, Folder 13)
      40 p.
      Inscription to Vladimir Horowitz from ? Herz, New York, 31 January 1940, inscribed on first leaf.
    - Konzert No. 4, G dur, für Pianoforte mit Orchester, op. 58. Leipzig: Ernst Eulenburg, n.d., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 85, Folder 14)
      Miniature score, 141 p.
      Plate number: E. E. 3805
      Fragile.
    - Rasshifrovka knigi eskizov. Za 1802-1803 gody. Betkhovena. Moskva: Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal'noe Izdatel'stvo, 1962., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 85, Folder 15)
      184 p.
      Plate number: M. 27998 G.
      Inscription in ink on title page from Mosiva Teshuy?, 1964 Oct. 21.
    - Sieben Bagatellen op. 33 für das Pianoforte. Stuttgart und Berlin: J. G. Cotta'sche Buchhandlung Nachfolger, 1902., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 16)
      21 p.
      Plate number: 34
      (Instruktive Ausgabe klassischer Klavierwerke.)
      Part of collected work? Bottom of pages have page nos. 82-101.
    - Sonata op. 30, no. 2 [for piano and violin]. New York: G. Schirmer, n.d., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 17)
      32 p.
      Plate number: 29522
      Cover, title page missing. Piano score only. Fragile.
    - Sonatas for pianoforte, vol. I London: Associated Board of the Royal Schools of Music (The Royal Academy of Music and the Royal College of Music), n.d., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 18)
      251 p.
      Plate number: A.B. 424, A.B. 232-242.
      Preface dated 1931; edited by Donald Francis Tovey and Harold Craxton.
    - Sonatas for pianoforte, vol. II. London: Associated Board of the Royal Schools of Music, n.d., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 19)
      245 p.
      Plate number: A.B. 425, A.B. 424, A.B. 243-253.
    - Sonatas for pianoforte, vol. III. London: Associated Board of the Royal Schools of Music (The Royal Academy of Music and the Royal College of Music), n.d., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 20)
      261 p.
      Plate number: A.B. 424, A.B. 254-263.
    - Sonate Appassionata (en fa mineur, opus 57). Paris: L'Edition d'Art, n.d., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 21)
      Facsimile. Letter, facsimile, in French pasted onto the inside front cover; small business card of Henry Le Boeuf laid inside front cover; inscribed note dated 1889 on first leaf (facsimile).
    - Sonate nr. 21, op. 53, Dem Grafen von Waldstein gewidmet. Kritisch-instructive Ausgabe von Eugen D'Albert. Leipzig: Otto Forberg, 1902., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 22)
      35 p.
      Plate number: 2813
      (L. van Beethoven sonaten für pianoforte. Kritisch-Instructive Ausgabe)
      Markings in pencil.
    - Sonaten und andere Werke für das Pianoforte, Zweiter Band. Stuttgart: Verlag der J. G. Cotta'schen Buchhandlung Nachfolger, 1898., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 23)
      54 p.
      Plate number: 33
      Pages missing at end.
    - Trio für piano-forte, violin und violoncello, 97tes werk. Wien: S. A. Steiner und Comp., n. d. [1816?], Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
      3 parts (piano, 50 p.; violino, 11 p.; violoncello, 11 p.)
      Plate number: S. et C. 2582.
      Signature on title page, Josephine Gossen. Bonn: N. Simrock pasted over original publisher imprint.
    - Variationen: für Klavier / Beethoven; herausgegeben von Mitarbeitern des Beethoven-Archivs durch Joseph Schmidt-Görg. München-Duisburg: G. Henle Verlag, 1961., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 86, Folder 24)
      253 p.
      Inscription from Rudi [Serkin] to Vladimir Horowitz on front cover verso.
    - Deux Etudes-Fantaisies pour piano, op. 25. Leipzig: M. Belaieff, 1898., Blumenfeld, Felix (Box 87, Folder 25)
      Plate number: 1553 1555
    - Polovetzer Tanz aus "Prince Igor". Berlin: N. Simrock, 1923., Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887 (Box 87, Folder 26)
      7 p.
      Plate number: 14519
      (Tanzweisen aus zwei Jahrhunderten.)
      Für Klavier zum Konzertgebrauch frei gesetzt von Felix Dyck.
      Inscription on front cover in ink from Felix Dyck to Vladimir Horowitz, 1933 Oct. 5.
    - The sleeping princess (La Princesse endormie): Ballade. Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, 1921., Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887 (Box 87, Folder 26)
      Plate number: ML-2847-6
      (Russian songs.)
    - [Concertos, piano, no. 2, op. 83, B major] Concert: Op. 83: No. 2: B-dur: für Pianoforte mit Begleitung des Orchesters / von Johannes Brahms. Berlin: N. Simrock, 1882., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 87, Folder 27-31)
      1 score (159 p.) + 60 parts.
      Plate number: 8263.
      Contains markings and labeled "Horowitz."
    - [Concertos, piano, no. 2, op. 83, B major; arr.] Konzert, op. 83. Berlin: N. Simrock, 1926., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 87, Folder 32)
      105 p.
      Plate number: 14801
      Two-piano score. Revisions-Ausgabe Mayer-Mahr.
      Vladimir Horowitz autograph on p. 3.
    - Intermezzo, op. 117, no. 2. Braunschweig: Henry Litolff's Verlag, n.d., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 87, Folder 33)
      Plate number: Collection Litolff No. 2732h
      (Collection Litolff Brahms Klavierwerke Compositions pour Piano à 2 mains.)
    - Klavier Sonate, op. 5, F moll. Berlin: N. Simrock, n.d., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 88, Folder 34)
      39 p.
      Plate number: 20101
      (Simrock Volks-Ausgabe. No. 1.2.3. Drei Sonaten für das Pianoforte componirt von Johannes Brahms.)
      Inscription in ink on front cover to Vladimir Horowitz from Georges B-?
    - Ungarische Tanze für das Pianoforte zu vier Händen. Berlin: N. Simrock, n.d., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 88, Folder 35)
      29 p.
      Plate number: 6999
      Heft II, 6-10. Fragile.
    - Vals I: As dur: Af op. 39 / Johs. Brahms. -- Aarhus: Kaabers Musikforlag, n.d., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 88, Folder 36)
      3 p.
      Plate number: 31.
      Vladimir Horowitz autograph and inscription in ink on p. 2 dated 10 October 1933 Copenhagen.
    - Variationen über ein thema von Paganini für Klavier zu 2 Händen, op. 35, Heft I. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 88, Folder 37)
      Plate number: 10098
      Herausgegeben von Emil von Sauer.
    - Variazioni sopra un tema di R. Schumann per Pianoforte, op. 9. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1929., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 88, Folder 38)
      Plate number: E.R. 1006
    - Walzer für das Pianoforte zu vier Händen, op. 39. Leipzig: J. Rieter-Biedermann, n.d. [1867], Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Box 88, Folder 39)
      Plate number: 524
      Part of bound collection.
      Arranged for two hands.
    - Sonatina für Klavier zu zwei Händen. Wiesbaden: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Busoni, Ferruccio, 1866-1924 (Box 88, Folder 40)
      Publisher's number: Edition Breitkopf Nr. 4948.
      Inscribed on inside front cover: "Natale 1987 to Maestro from Giuliana."
    - Narrative (Remembrance of things past). New York: J. Fischer & Bro., 1942., Chasins, Abram, 1903-1987 (Box 88, Folder 41)
      15 p.
      Plate number: J.F.& B. 7871-14
      2 copies. Note from composer taped to front cover, dated 1/23/42 on first copy, note inscribed by composer in ink on front cover of second copy, dated 11/20/46.
    - "Shvanda" fantasy. Based on two themes from Weinberger's opera "Shvanda". New York: Associated Music Publishers, Inc., 1940., Chasins, Abram, 1903-1987 (Box 88, Folder 41)
      14 p.
      Inscribed in ink by composer on cover, Xmas 1940.
    - Three Chinese pieces, op. 5. Flirtation in a Chinese garden. New York: J. Fischer and Bro., 1925., Chasins, Abram, 1903-1987 (Box 88, Folder 41)
      Plate number: J.F.& B. 5593-3
      Inscribed in ink by composer on cover, dated 2/29/30.
    - Three Chinese pieces. Rush hour in Hong Kong. New York: J. Fischer & Bro., 1925., Chasins, Abram, 1903-1987 (Box 88, Folder 41)
      Plate number: J.F.& B. 5590-5
      Inscribed in ink by composer on cover, dated 4/29/30.
    - Twenty-four preludes for the piano. Book I. Six preludes. Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, 1928., Chasins, Abram, 1903-1987 (Box 88, Folder 41)
      20 p.
      Plate number: 76124-19
    - Twenty-four preludes for the piano. Book IV. Six preludes. Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, 1928., Chasins, Abram, 1903-1987 (Box 88, Folder 41)
      Plate number: 76141-14
      Inscribed in ink by composer on cover.
    - Ballade pour le Piano, op. 38. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d. [1840], Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849
      11 p.
      Plate number: 6330
      First edition
    - Barcarolle op. 60, Fis dur. Mainz: B. Schott's Sohne, 1918., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 42)
      Plate number: Edition Schott No. 0422
      Neu-Ausgabe von Emil Sauer.
    - Complete works for the piano, book X. Rondos. New York: G. Schirmer, 1916, 1934., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 43)
      52 p.
      (Schirmer's library of musical classics, volume 1554.)
      Edited and fingered by Carl Mikuli.
      Markings on p. 46.
    - Complete works for the piano, book VII. Scherzi and Fantasy. New York: G. Schirmer, 1915, 1934, 1943., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 44)
      92 p.
      Plate number: 36395
      (Schirmer's library of musical classics, volume 1556.)
    - Complete works, v. V. Scherzos. Warsaw: Fryderyk Chopin Institute Polish Music Publications, 1950., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 45)
      110 p.
      Plate number: P.W.M. 236
      (Chopin complete works.)
      Edited by I. J. Paderewski.
      Vladimir Horowitz's autograph (initials) in ink on front cover.
    - Fantaisie-Impromptu, op. 66., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 46)
      p. 39-47.
    - In memoriam. Henry Wadsworth Longfellow's funeral march. Marche Funèbre. New York: R. A. Saalfield, n.d., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849
    - Mazurek as dur (la bemol majeur). Warszawa: Gebethner i Wolff, n.d., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 47)
      Plate number: G. 6905 W.
      Preface dated May 1930. Inscription in ink inside front cover. Clipping from magazine included inside cover.
    - Mazurkas. New York: G. Schirmer, 1915, 1943., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 48)
      151 p.
      Plate number: 25503
      (Schirmer's library of musical classics, volume 28.)
    - Mazurkas für Klavier zu 2 handen. Braunschweig: Henry Litolff's Verlag, n.d., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 49)
      111 p.
      Plate number: 1047
    - Mazurken. München: G. Henle Verlag, 1975., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 49)
      169 p.
    - Nocturne, op. 9, no. 3. New York: G. Schirmer, n.d., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 50)
      Plate number: 11052
      (Frederic Chopin. Works for the pianoforte)
      Revised and fingered by C. Mikuli.
    - Nocturne, op. 15 no. 2. New York: G, Schirmer, 1915., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 88, Folder 50)
      Plate number: 11054
      Revised and fingered by Rafael Joseffy.
    - Nocturnes. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 89, Folder 51)
      96 p.
      Plate number: 9025
      Kritisch revidiert und mit Fingersatz versehen von Herrmann Scholtz. 2 copies.
    - Oxford original edition of Frederic Chopin, volume 1. London: Oxford University Press, n.d., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 89, Folder 52)
      Edited by Edouard Ganche. Pages numbered within individual works, not sequentially. Fragile.
    - Oxford original edition of Frederic Chopin, volume 3. London: Oxford University Press, n.d., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 (Box 89, Folder 53)
      Edited by Edouard Ganche. Pages numbered within individual works, not sequentially.
    - Trios Manuscrits de Chopin. Paris: Dorbon Ainé, Les Manuscrits des Maîtres Anciens de la Musique, n.d., Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849
      67 p.
      Facsimile. Contents: Ballade en fa; Valse op. 69, n. 1 (Valse de l'Adieu); Berceuse.
    - Oeuvres complètes. Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, [1802-1819]., Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832
      Includes: XII sonates pour le pianoforte, Cahier I, (120 p.). -- IX sonates pour le Pianoforte, Cahier II, (122 p.). -- IX sonates pour le pianoforte, Cahier III, (124 p.). -- VI sonates a quatre mains et I sonate pour deux pianofortes, Cahier IV, (112 p.). -- XVII sonates pour le pianoforte, Cahier V, (100 p.) [2 copies, unidentified signature, date 1869 inscribed on first leaf, part of title page cut out of second copy]. -- VII sonates, I toccata, et II caprices pour le pianoforte, Cahier VI, (110 p.) [2 copies, title page missing, unidentified signature, date 1869 inscribed on first leaf of second copy]. - - 8 sonates pour le pianoforte avec accompagnement de violon ou flute et violoncelle, Cahier VII, (3 parts - piano (73 p.), violino o flauto (15 p.), violoncello (13 p.)). -- 7 sonates pour le pianoforte seul; 3 sonates pour le pianoforte avec accompagnement de violon et violoncelle, Cahier VIII, (3 parts - piano (80 p.), violino (12 p.), violoncello (10 p.)). -- 6 sonates pour le pianoforte; 3 sonates pour le pianoforte seul; 3 sonates pour le pianoforte avec accompagnement de violon et violoncelle, Cahier IX, (3 parts - piano (88 p.), violino (10 p.), violoncello (8 p.). -- 8 Sonates pour le pianoforte; 3 sonates pour le pianoforte seul; 5 sonates pour le pianoforte avec accompagnement de violon ou flute, Cahier X, ( 2 parts - piano (93 p.), violino o flauto (14 p.), Plate number: 1406, [piano and violino o flauto parts only]. -- Six sonates progressives et doigtées, 24 valses, une sonate et la chasse pour le pianoforte, Cahier XI, (91 p.), Plate number: 1834. -- Quatre sonates pour le pianoforte avec accompagnement de violon, un caprice, preludes et cadences pour le pianoforte seul et une sonate a quatre mains, Cahier XII, (2 parts - piano (75 p.), violino (6 p.), Plate number: 2426, [Ricordi pasted over original publisher citation]. -- 11 sonates pour le pianoforte dont 5 avec accompagnement d'un violon et 6 avec violon et violoncelle, Cahier XIII, (75 p.), [piano part only, lacks violon and violoncello parts].
      Vols. 1-13.
      Répertoire International des Sources Musicales (RISM) C3155.
      Only one other complete set reported (Vienna). No copy of any volume reported in the U.S.A.
    - Sonaten für Pianoforte, neue Ausgabe. Offenbach: Joh. André, [ca. 1856]., Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832
      Plate number: 4523 III
      Lacks Anton Schindler's Beilage.
    - [Sonates, piano. Selections] Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832 (Box 89, Folder 54)
      45 p.
      Plate number: 16927
      Title page missing.
    - Twelve sonatas for the piano, book 1. New York: G. Schirmer, 1896., Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832 (Box 90, Folder 55)
      Plate number: 127831-127837
      (Schirmer's library of musical classics, volume 385)
      Edited and fingered by G. Buonamici.
    - Fifteen variations and finale in C minor for piano on an original theme, op. 37. [London: Chappell, 1959?], Coke, R. Sacheverell (Box 90, Folder 56)
      31 p.
      Plate number: 44612
    - Our town. Three piano excerpts from the film score. New York: Boosey & Hawkes, Inc., 1945., Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 (Box 90, Folder 57)
      10 p.
      Plate number: B.Pa Solo 60-8
    - Dodici Sonate per violino e pianoforte. Opera Quinta. Volume Primo. Milano: G. Ricordi & C., 1935., Corelli, Arcangelo, 1653-1713 (Box 90, Folder 58)
      2 parts (piano, 60 p.; violino, 25 p.)
      Plate number: E.R. 1749
      Inscribed in ink on title page of piano part, dated Aprile 1936.
    - New grand march for the piano forte. London: J. B. Cramer, [ca. 1824-1844]., Cramer, J. B. (Johann Baptist), 1771-1858
      4 p.
      Plate number: 611
    - British Grenadiers' march, with variations for the piano forte, op. 81. London: J. B. Cramer, [ca. 1824-1844]., Czerny, Carl, 1791-1857
      Plate number: 232
    - Impromptus or brilliant variations on a favorite cotillion by Gallenberg for the piano forte, op. 36. London: T. Boosey & Co., [ca. 1816-1854]., Czerny, Carl, 1791-1857
    - La Ricordanza. Rode's favorite air sung by Madame Catalani, arranged for the piano forte, op. 33. London: Goulding D'Almaine & Co., [ca. 1823-1834]., Czerny, Carl, 1791-1857
      Plate number: Ricordanza (C. Czerny.)
    - Über den richtigen Vortrag der Säntkucgeb Beethoven'schen Klavierwerke. S.l.: Universal Edition, 1963., Czerny, Carl, 1791-1857 (Box 90, Folder 58)
      121 p.; 31 cm.
      Edited by Paul Badura-Skoda.
      Publisher's number: UE 13 340
      Inscription on front fly leaf: To Volodja with affection, love and friendship from Rudi [Serkin] October 1st, 1963.
    - Douze etudes, livre I-II. Paris: Durand & Cie., 1916., Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 (Box 90, Folder 59)
      27, 30 p.
      Plate number: D. & F. 9406-7.
    - Fêtes. Transcription pour piano par V. Leyetchkiss., Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 (Box 90, Folder 59)
      30 p.
      Photocopy of manuscript. Page of information on Vladimir Leyetchkiss included.
    - L'isle joyeuse pour le piano, transcription pour orchestre. Paris: A. Durand & Fils, 1904., Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 (Box 90, Folder 60)
      69 p.
      Plate number: D. & F. 10246.
      Transcription pour orchestre de B. Molinari.
    - Izbrannye p'esy: klia fortepiano; Redaktor - sostavitel Iu. Oleveniv. Moskva: Izdatel'stvo Muzyka, 1973., Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 (Box 90, Folder 60)
      Contents: Clair de lune, En bateau, Reflets dans l'eau, La neige danse, ...Des pas sur la neige, ...La fille aux cheveux de lin, ...La sérénade interrompue, ...La cathédrale engloutie, ...Minstrels, La plus que lente (valse), Étude pour les degrés chromatiques, Fêtes. Corrections pasted over original notation in several spots.
      62 p.
      Plate number: 7855
    - Six barcarolles et cinq impromptus pour piano. Paris: J. Hamelle, 1926., Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924 (Box 90, Folder 61)
      101 p.
      Plate number: J. 1897 H., J. 2499 H., J. 2500 H., J. 2631 H., J. 3791 H., J. 4013 H., J. 1896 H., J. 2119 H., J. 2125 H., J. 7347 H., J. 7347 bis H.
    - Prélude, aria et final pour piano. Paris: J. Hamelle, n.d., Franck, César, 1822-1890 (Box 90, Folder 62)
      27 p.
      Plate number: J. 2852 H.
      (César Franck. Oeuvres pour piano à deux mains.)
    - Gavotte, transcribed for Frau Clara Schumann by Johannes Brahms. New York: G. Schirmer, 1885., Gluck, Christoph Willibald, Ritter von, 1714-1787 (Box 90, Folder 63)
      Plate number: 3796
      (Classic and modern. A collection of compositions for the piano, revised and fingered by eminent masters.)
      Fingered by A. R. Parsons.
    - First valse brilliant in Ab, op. 26. New York: G. Schirmer, 1884., Godard, Benjamin, 1849-1895 (Box 90, Folder 63)
      Plate number: 3532
      (Benjamin Godard compositions for pianoforte.)
    - Miniatures for piano four hands, volume 1, miscellaneous nos. 1-7. New York: Carl Fischer, 1918., Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938 (Box 90, Folder 64)
      41 p.
      Plate number: C C 20690-4, C.C. 20581-8, C C 20777-6, C C 20686-4, C C 20691-4, C C 20688-6, C C 20861-8.
      (Godowsky miniatures for piano four hands in six volumes.)
      Vladimir Horowitz signature on front cover.
    - Passacaglia for the pianoforte. New York: Carl Fischer, 1928., Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938 (Box 90, Folder 64)
      42 p.
      Plate number: 24518-41
      Note inscribed by composer to Vladimir Horowitz on first leaf.
    - Three suites (newly revised edition) for piano four hands. New York: Carl Fischer, 1918., Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938 (Box 90, Folder 64)
      Plate number: C C 20914-10, C C 20915-10, C C 20741-10
      (Leopold Godowsky "Miniatures" in six volumes.)
    - Grotesque fantasie. The banjo. An American sketch. New York: William Hall and Son, 1855., Gottschalk, Louis Moreau, 1829-1869
      Plate number: 3345
      First edition.
    - At the circus. New York: J. Fischer and Bro., 1944., Grechaninov, Aleksandr Tikhonovich, 1864-1956 (Box 90, Folder 65)
      Plate number: J.F. & B. 8050-2
      "Sonia" on front cover.
    - Les fleurs d'automne, op. 106, no. 1. Mainz: B. Schott's Sohne, n.d., Grechaninov, Aleksandr Tikhonovich, 1864-1956 (Box 90, Folder 65)
      Plate number: 32435
      Inscribed in ink on cover.
    - La journée d'un enfant, op. 109. Mainz: B. Schott's Sohne, 1927., Grechaninov, Aleksandr Tikhonovich, 1864-1956 (Box 90, Folder 65)
      Plate number: 31993
      Presentation "A Mlle. Horowitz" by the composer on front cover.
    - Eight lyric pieces for piano, op. 12. New York: Carl Fischer, 1914., Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907 (Box 90, Folder 65)
      Contents: Arietta, Waltz, Watchman's song, Fairy-dance, Popular melody, Norwegian melody, Album-leaf.
      16 p.
      Plate number: 11101-1, 11102-2, 7731-2, 11103-2, 11104-2, 11105-2, 6725- 2.
      Edited by Andor Pinter.
    - Sonata for piano. New York: G. Schirmer, 1921., Griffes, Charles Tomlinson, 1884-1920 (Box 90, Folder 65)
      Plate number: 30184
    - Kompositionen für Klavier, Heft I, Suite I-VIII. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 (Box 90, Folder 66)
      83 p.
      Plate number: 7903
      (Kompositionen für Klavier von G. F. Handel.)
      Herausgegeben von Adolf Ruthardt.
    - XV airs et chansons et Arianne à Naxos, scène avec accompagnement du pianoforte. Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809
      (Oeuvres de J. Haydn. Cahier VIII.)
      Répertoire International des Sources Musicales (RISM) H-2470. Three copies in the U.S.A.
    - Klaviersonaten: Band I / Joseph Haydn; Nach den Eigenschriften Originalausgaben oder Ältesten Abschriften herausgegeben von Georg Feder. München-Duisburg: G. Henle Verlag, 1963., Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809 (Box 90, Folder 67)
      125 p.